# Devesh Srivastava

#### LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Lead full stack developer with total 14 years of experience in frontend, backend with single responsive page including React, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Node.js, .Net,C#, MVC, CI/CD deployment Azure/AWS cloud, Docker/ Kubernetesand lead team across a range of agile centric and waterfall delivery model. Worked on Technical Lead role at onshore client site for more than 5 Years in UK.



devesh.kr.sri@gmail.com 🔀

(+91) 9999305585

Delhi, India 💡

deveshprofile.herokuapp.com/

linkedin.com/in/devesh-srivastava- in 94268516

devesh.kr.srivastava@gmail.com [S]

github.com/deveshprojectwork ()

#### **SKILLS**

ReactJS, Redux, Hook EmberJS, Webpack, Babel Material UI, Forma 36, Prime React Angular HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap Asp.net, C#, MVC JavaScript, Typescript

BACK END - Node.js, .Net Core API

GraphQL, REST APIs

Microservices

Git, GitHub, TFS, Jira

TESTING -: Jest, Karma, Jasmine, RSpec

DATABASE- MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

DEPLOYMENT: Jenkin pipeline with Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible

Heroku, AWS, Azure-devops

Agile, Kanban

OAuth, JWT

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Digital Squad, NBS UK

03/2018 - Present Accenture UK

Working as a Full Stack Developer in Leading UK Bank in mortgages to facilitate its digital transformation form on-premise to cloud.

- Solution Design of overall front end and back end application for digital mortgage sales using React. JS, Redux, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL & REST API, CSS3, HTML5, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js & CI/CD.
- Design and Developed Rails and Ruby application for the Digital platform with R spec and Capybara testing framework and using PostgreSQL with Heroku deployment.
- Setup CI/CD pipeline with Jenkins and Azure Devops to deploy applications to multiple production server in Azure/AWS cloud with Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible.
- Delivering Solution Concepts, estimation for upgrading and supporting legacy application to .net application.
- Led end-to-end technical consulting engagements for enterprise clients building internal software development with performed planning, estimation, coding, bug fixing, code reviews.
- Managed projects with agile methodologies in IIRA via user stories and customer issues.

## LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER NATIONWIDE BUILDING SOCIETY, UK

04/2015 - 03/2018 Accenture UK

Designed and developed web-based components for a variety of applications in an agile development setting in MDC.

- Create custom components in React JS, Redux (internal UI library) that can be used company wide so that we have common UI across applications.
- Support the development of the Angular application with Core API with Sql Server.
- Design and implementation of the 99.99% up-time REST API for the business-critical banking application.
- Collaborates with client-side business leaders to scope IT process reviews, allocate resources, and oversees service transitions e.g. analyzing service data, interviewing users, and recommending solutions that support clients' strategic objectives.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### CBIA Project - Accenture UK/India

09/2011 - 03/2015 Worked with a large UK financial banking projects for Digital applications.

Achievements/Tasks

- Architected and designed enterprise applications for project using Angular, AWS Lambda, & SQL server.
- Design and implementation of the 99.99% up-time REST API for the business-critical online service.
- Build technical architecture for reporting applications.
- Supported MVC, .net, C# project to build front end application.
- Consulted in a redesign of the company's website, resulting in a 25% increase in traffic.

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ITALFONDIARIO Project

09/2009 - 09/2011 Accenture India

Worked with large financial banking applications for the development and support of applications.

- Lead Development team for banking applications. Developed web applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, and
- Implement the module based on the change request, along with the build, code review, unit testing & deployment of the application.
- Ensure proper documentation and reports in all stages of the application development life cycle.

### **EDUCATION**

## MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION IGNORE, DELHI

08/2001 - 05/2005

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

CertifiedScrumMaster®(CSM) form Scrum Alliance Inc.

Microsoft Azure Cloud Certified (Developer and Administrator)

Accenture India/UK

#### NATIONWIDE BUILDING SOCIETY

PRIDE AWARD AT ACCENTURE FOR OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION TO THE PROJECT IN 2018 & 2019

#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

ACCENTURE PRIVATE LIMITED (08/2009 - Present)

Team Lead

PATNI COMPUTER SYSTEM (01/2008 - 08/2009)

SR.Software Engineer

FCF Software Solution LTD (06/2006 - 07/2007)

Software Engineer

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React.JS, Ruby on Rails, Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap **Frontend** 

**Backend** Node.js, .Net Framework, RESTApi, TDD, and .Net Core API

Cloud platforms AWS, Heroku, Azure (Web Service, Function, Storage, Database)

**Testing** Mocha, Jest, Selenium, JUnit, NUnit

**Database** MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MYSQL, SQL Server

Collaboration Confluence, JIRA, Agile

Dev-Ops/CI-CD Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Ansible

**Domain** Banking, Finance, Manufacturing